<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: recruiting | Sam Kottler]]></title>
  <link href="http://samkottler.com/blog/categories/recruiting/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://samkottler.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-22T06:31:49-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://samkottler.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sam Kottler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Tale of 31 Emails]]></title>
    <link href="http://samkottler.com/blog/2012/05/28/a-tale-of-31-emails/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-28T08:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://samkottler.com/blog/2012/05/28/a-tale-of-31-emails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've received 31 emails, 9 phone calls, 12 LinkedIn connection requests, and a text message over the past 7 days from technical recruiters. While some of these numbers are largely my own fault (i.e. my phone number was published publicly on LinkedIn), those numbers are truly obscene. They are even more aggregious when you take into consideration the fact that not a single one of the messages encouraged me to pursue opportunities presented. Part of that is because I'm incredibly happy at Venmo, but given the kind of companies I'm receiving communication from (Tumblr, Gilt Group, etc) it seems that at least <em>some</em> of them would be interesting enough to start a conversation.</p>

<h3>The Volume</h3>

<p>First off, the numbers alone are incredible.</p>

<p><strong>31 emails</strong>: not one of them went into my inbox. Every single email I received from a recruiter got archived and tagged. I look at these later, if at all.</p>

<p><strong>9 phone calls</strong>: 2 of which got answered. I generally ignore phone calls from numbers not in my address book. I'm not sure why I answered these two, but the conversation was short; I spent most of the time trying to get the recruiter to stop talking long enough so I could ask them to remove me from their system before I hung up.</p>

<p><strong>12 LinkedIn connection requests or messages</strong>: I mark these "appropriate, but not at this time" unless they are abusive in some way. I don't read them and just ignore the request to connect.</p>

<p><strong>1 text message</strong>: I've been stalked by a recruiter for over three months. I've asked her repeatedly to stop contacting me. I've spoken to her boss and the company she is representing. All promised me results but none delivered them. She uses different numbers to text me and ask whether I'm interested in a position. I have over a dozen of her phone numbers blocked by my cell phone carrier.</p>

<h3>The Words</h3>

<blockquote><p>I am currently recruiting for a Senior Systems Engineer (Sr. UNIX/Linux Administrator) with either (Red Hat, MySQL or Puppet) experience for Example.com in New York City.</p></blockquote>

<p>Right after reading that line, I was confused. The fact that the recruiter listed these items separately, but later globs them together is concerning - it shows a clear lack of understanding about the systems being used at the company. Here's the kicker:</p>

<blockquote><p>Rock Star candidates must have a strong (Java or Python) programming experience within a fast/heavy volume traffic environment to be able to keep up with the rest of this 100 plus technical team.</p></blockquote>

<p>This part seems to be blatantly wrong. I <em>think</em> was the recruiter intended to say is "Rock Star candidates must have a strong background in running systems built with Java or Python." Again,another concerning sign about a lack of understanding.</p>

<p>Since when was the term "rock star" (which is BS anyhow) capitalized like a title? <strong>Red Flag</strong></p>

<h3>How It Should Be</h3>

<p>Stop having your recruiter email me. Frankly, I have little confidence in recruiters, even those working in house. Instead, have an engineer reach out to me. An engineer will be able to speak to me honestly and answer deeper questions in a more concrete manner than any technical recruiter. Come to an event where I'm speaking and approach me; I'd love to talk to you!</p>

<p>Stop bombarding me with bullshit that I filter out of my inbox and read periodically for a good laugh. Understand the positions you're peddling and make a strong effort to convey the role in an accurate way. Most importantly, if you're genuinely interested in having me work for you, make an effort to connect. Accurately convey the position and demonstrate a true interest in me. Stop referring to technical people as "assets" or "resources" and start talking about our experience, work, and how we can help the organizations you represent be technically and culturally better.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
